All right good afternoon everybody
大家下午好
Welcome!good to see you
欢迎！很高兴见到你
Hope you all have started your attack labs
希望你们都开始攻击实验室
Everybody started? be a good time to start I think
大家都开始了？我认为是开始的好时机
Anyway I hope you're enjoying it, that's a that's a new one this semester that's
无论如何，我希望你喜欢它，这是一个新学期，这是一个新学期
I think really interesting and modern and current
我认为真的很有趣，现代和当前
Okay today we're going to...
好的今天我们要......
Today we're going to talk about something called the memory hierarchy
今天我们要讨论一些叫做内存层次结构的东西
Now so far in the class we've thought of memory
到目前为止，在课堂上我们已经想到了记忆
When we're looking at our assembly language programs
当我们查看汇编语言程序时
We've thought of memory as an array of bytes
我们已经将内存视为一个字节数组
It's the big array of bytes that we can access with that an index called an address
这是我们可以使用一个名为地址的索引访问的大字节数组
But in actuality the memory system is a very complex hierarchy of devices
但实际上，内存系统是一个非常复杂的设备层次结构
That provides this abstraction of this this large linear array
这提供了这个大型线性阵列的抽象
And so today we're going to look at how memory hierarchies are built
所以今天我们将看看如何构建内存层次结构
And why they're built the way they are
为什么他们按照他们的方式建造
And what we'll see is that this sort of beautiful confluence of the properties of storage devices
而我们将看到的是存储设备属性的这种美妙融合
And the properties of programs come together to create this...
程序的属性汇集起来创造了这个......
This beautiful design called a memory hierarchy
这个美丽的设计称为内存层次结构
So we're going to quickly kind of do a high-level tour of storage technologies and trends
因此，我们将很快对存储技术和趋势进行高级别的访问
We're not going to go into a whole lot of detail
我们不打算详细介绍
The point in looking at these at these the properties of these technologies is that
从这些技术的特性来看这些技术的关键在于
There are some fundamental properties that determine their performance and their speed
有一些基本属性决定了它们的性能和速度
And determine limits on their performance and speed
并确定其性能和速度的限制
And so I want you to have a,you know, just some high-level idea of what those what those properties are
所以我希望你有一个关于那些属性是什么的高层次想法
And then we'll look at a property of programs called locality of reference
然后我们将看一个称为参考局部的程序的属性
And we'll see how that locality and the properties of storage devices
我们将看到该地点和存储设备的属性
Come together to suggest this design of memory systems as a hierarchy
聚集在一起建议将这种内存系统设计作为一种层次结构
Okay so we'll look at memories first
好的，我们先看看回忆
Now the the workhorse memory is called a random access memory or RAM
现在主力内存被称为随机存取存储器或RAM
I'm sure it's traditionally packaged up as a chip
我确信它传统上被打包成芯片
And then you put multiple chips together to form your main memory
然后你把多个芯片组合在一起形成你的主存
And there's a basic storage unit called a cell which where each cell stores one bit
并且有一个称为单元的基本存储单元，每个单元存储一位
Okay now there's a RAM comes in two varieties
好的，现在有两种RAM
There's a DRAM and DRAM and they're distinguished by the way that those cells are implemented
有一个DRAM和DRAM，他们的特点是这些单元的实现方式
So in
所以
and SRAM requires it's more complex than DRAM it requires like 4,6 transistors per bit whereas DRAM only requires a one transistor
SRAM要求它比DRAM要复杂得多，如每位4,6个晶体管，而DRAM只需要一个晶体管
Okay so you'll see that SRAM are going to be more expensive lots more expensive
好的，所以你会发现SRAM会更昂贵更贵
Because they're more complex each cell is more complex
因为它们更复杂，每个细胞都更复杂
But they're also much faster like ten order magnitude faster than DRAMs
但它们的速度也比DRAM快10个数量级
And they have there's some other properties too like
他们还有其他一些属性
SRAM constantly,a DRAM constantly needs to be refreshed
SRAM不断，需要不断更新DRAM
If you don't hit it with a voltage
如果你没有用电​​压击中它
It loses the charge whereas DRAM while it needs to be plugged in
当需要插入DRAM时，它会丢失电荷而DRAM则会丢失
And and have an electric charge it doesn't need to be refreshed
并且有一个电荷，它不需要刷新
SRAM is a lot more reliable than DRAM so it
SRAM比DRAM更可靠
There's less need for error detection and correction
不太需要进行错误检测和纠正
And there and so because of this difference right the SRAMs are costlier smaller and faster than DRAMs
而且由于存在这种差异，因此SRAM比DRAM更小，速度更快
We find SRAMs being used in these small fast memories on chip called cache memories
我们发现SRAM被用在芯片上的这些小型快速存储器中，称为高速缓冲存储器
And we're going to learn all about those on Thursday
我们将在星期四学习所有这些
And then DRAM is the workhorse used in main memories and the frame buffers associated with graphics cards
然后DRAM是主存储器中使用的主力和与图形卡相关的帧缓冲器
Now DRAM and SRAM are volatile in the sense that if they're powered off they lose all the information right so this is why
现在DRAM和SRAM是易失性的，如果它们断电就会丢失所有信息，所以这就是原因
When you turn your computer off you have to you lose everything in your memory
当你关闭电脑时，你必须失去记忆中的一切
And you have to when you turn it back on you have to sort of reload everything from your disk
当你重新打开它时，你必须重新加载磁盘上的所有东西
There's a different another kind of memory called a nonvolatile memory which retains its information when it's powered off
还有另一种称为非易失性存储器的存储器，它在断电时保留其信息
And there's a whole bunch of these things that so called up read-only memory
并且有很多这些东西被称为只读内存
So the generic name for these nonvolatile memories is read only memories ROM
因此，这些非易失性存储器的通用名称是只读存储器ROM
And there's a whole bunch of different kinds sort of going back in time the original read only memories were ROMs
而且有很多不同类型的东西可以追溯到最初的只读存储器是ROM
And they can only be programmed once when the chip was produced
并且它们只能在芯片生产时编程一次
And then over time gradually over period of like 20 or 30 years
然后逐渐超过20或30年的时间
There were improvements in the way that ROMs could be programmed and in how they were erased
ROM的编程方式和删除方式都有所改进
So they could be reprogrammed
所以他们可以重新编程
The what we have today the the modern form of read only memories is called flash memory
我们今天所拥有的现代形式的只读存储器被称为闪存
Which provides the capability of erasing you can erase just chunks of the the flash memory called blocks
它提供了擦除功能，你可以只删除称为块的闪存块
And then the downside is that these things wear out after about a hundred thousand erasers
然后缺点是这些东西在大约十万个橡皮擦之后磨损了
Okay so you can erase and reprogram a hundred thousand times and then it's your bricked
好的，你可以擦除和重新编程十万次，然后它就是你的砖块
Now that these nonvolatile memories are show up in with
现在这些非易失性存储器已经出现了
So called firmware which is software
所谓的固件是软件
That's that's programmed into a ROM
那就是编程到ROM中
And you see those in the BIOS of computers so when you power on your computer
你可以在计算机的BIOS中看到那些，当你打开电脑时
The very first instructions that execute are stored in a ROM right
执行的第一个指令存储在ROM右侧
If you're wondered like where do those things come from so they're stored in ROM
如果你想知道这些东西来自哪里，那么它们就存储在ROM中
And then there's a boot process where gradually more and more information is
然后是一个启动过程，逐渐有越来越多的信息
And instructions are loaded into memory
并且指令被加载到内存中
You know IO.IO devices have little computers in them call controllers
你知道IO.IO设备中只有很少的计算机呼叫控制器
These controllers consist of instructions and data that are that are stored in ROMs
这些控制器由存储在ROM中的指令和数据组成
And you see them all over the place in these solid state disks
你可以在这些固态硬盘中看到它们
That to the system look like a rotating disk
系统看起来像一个旋转磁盘
But they're built of flash memories
但它们是由闪存构成的
Okay and these are you see these in thumb drives smartphones tablets and laptops
好的，这些是你在拇指驱动器智能手机平板电脑和笔记本电脑中看到的
And they're even starting to show up in servers now
他们现在甚至开始出现在服务器中
So the memories are connected to the CPU using sort of wires that are collectively called buses
因此，存储器使用统称为总线的电线连接到CPU
Okay so data flows across the wires back and forth from the,we have the CPU chip
好的，所以数据来自电线来回传输，我们有CPU芯片
And it consists of register file these are the general-purpose registers %rax, %rdi and so on
它由寄存器文件组成，这些是通用寄存器％rax，％rdi等
And there's an arithmetic logic unit that reads and writes data from the register files
并且有一个算术逻辑单元，用于从寄存器文件中读取和写入数据
And then manipulates that data in some way by doing some kind of arithmetic operation or some logical operation
然后通过某种算术运算或某种逻辑运算以某种方式操纵该数据
And if instructions need to access memory
如果指令需要访问内存
So if there's you're doing a move,a move instruction that reads or writes to memory
因此，如果你正在进行移动，那么读取或写入内存的移动指令
Then that's handled by a bus interface which is connected to a what we'll call a system bus
然后由总线接口处理，该接口连接到我们称之为系统总线的接口
And then that's connected to an I/O bridge and this
然后它连接到I / O桥和这个
This is another collection of chips,Intel calls this what I'm calling the I/O bridge,they call the chipset
这是另一个芯片集合，英特尔称之为我所称的I / O桥，他们称之为芯片组
Okay but it's it's a collection of chips separate from the process the CPU chip
好吧，但这是一个与CPU芯片分开的芯片集合
And then the I/O bridge is connected to another bus called the memory bus which connects the main memory
然后I / O桥连接到另一个称为内存总线的总线，该总线连接主存储器
Okay now this is kind of an abstraction I don't want you to take this too literally
好吧，现在这是一种抽象，我不希望你太过于字面意思
But it gives you the idea of how information flows in the system
但它让你了解信息如何在系统中流动
Okay modern modern systems use proprietary bus designs and they're very arcane and increasingly complex
好的现代现代系统使用专有总线设计，它们非常神秘且越来越复杂
So we're just going to use a fairly simple abstraction for these bus architectures
因此，我们将对这些总线架构使用相当简单的抽象
Now when is,now suppose you do a load operation like movq
现在什么时候，现在假设你执行像movq这样的加载操作
The eight bytes at address a into %rax
地址a中的八个字节为％rax
Okay so we call that a load because we're loading from the point of view of the CPU
好的，所以我们称之为负载，因为我们从CPU的角度加载
We're loading data into the CPU
我们正在将数据加载到CPU中
But we're loading and we're loading data from memory into the CPU
但我们正在加载，我们正在将内存中的数据加载到CPU中
So when the CPU executes movq instruction like this
所以当CPU执行这样的movq指令时
It first places the address of A on the memory bus
它首先将A的地址放在内存总线上
And then the main memory census that address and it reads the contents the eight bytes at address A
然后是主存储器人口普查，它解决了地址A中8个字节的内容
So it retrieves the word 8 byte word from address a and places it back on the bus
因此它从地址a检索字8字节字并将其放回总线上
The those bits travel through the I/O bridge to the bus interface
这些位通过I / O桥传输到总线接口
And then the CPU reads the the word x from the data word x from the bus and in composition to register %rax
然后CPU从总线的数据字x中读取字x，并在合成中读取％rax
Okay so it's now writing is is similar again
好的，现在写作再次类似
So here we're doing a move instruction movq from %rax into address A main memory
所以这里我们正在做一个从％rax到地址A主存储器的移动指令movq
Okay so the the CPU starts as before by placing the address a on the bus
好的，所以CPU通过将地址a放在总线上而像以前一样启动
Main memory reads that address and then it waits for the data to arrive on the bus
主存储器读取该地址，然后等待数据到达总线
So the CPU then places the contents of %rax on the bus
然后CPU将％rax的内容放在总线上
Those contents travel across to main memory
这些内容传播到主存储器
Which then reads the reads that word from the bus and stores it at address A
然后，它从总线读取该字的读取并将其存储在地址A中
Ok so that the point of all this is that operations that occur
好的，所有这一切都是发生的操作
You know reads and writes of registers
你知道寄存器的读写
Because the register file is very close to the ALU, these happen in on the order of a few cycles
因为寄存器文件非常靠近ALU，所以这些发生在几个周期的数量级
Ok register,the register very close to the ALU
好注册，寄存器非常接近ALU
So those operations are very happened very quickly
所以这些操作非常快
Whereas memories actually this is a set of chips that are very far away relatively speaking from the CPU
而记忆实际上这是一组与CPU相对较远的芯片
And there's a lot going on in when if you have to read or write memory there's
如果你必须读取或写入内存，那么会发生很多事情
It you have to do multiple operations on the bus,data has to travel propagate across that bus all this stuff takes time
你必须在总线上做多个操作，数据必须通过该总线传播所有这些东西需要时间
So memory operations reads and writes are typically
因此，内存操作通常是读写操作
You know maybe 50 nanoseconds 100 nanoseconds whereas operations that occur between registers are sub nanosecond
你知道可能是50纳秒100纳秒，而寄存器之间发生的操作是亚纳秒
On the order of so you're talking about a one to two orders of magnitude difference
按顺序，所以你说的是一到两个数量级的差异
If you have to go off chip to to retrieve something from memory
如果你不得不离开芯片从内存中检索一些东西
Ok so that's the first sort of big takeaway item about memory systems
好的，这是关于内存系统的第一个重要的外卖项目
Now in other popular storage technology is rotating disks
现在其他流行的存储技术是旋转磁盘
And I don't know if you've ever torn one apart they're kind of interesting there's a series of platters
而且我不知道你是否曾经撕开它们，它们有点有趣，还有一系列拼盘
Each platter is coated with a magnetic material
每个盘片都涂有磁性材料
And then and then bits ones and zeros are encoded in that magnetic material
然后，然后在该磁性材料中编码位1和0
And then there's this arm that can it's it's hinged right here
然后就是这只手臂就可以直接铰接在这里了
And then it can it floats over the platter so it floats on a thin layer of air over the platter
然后它可以漂浮在盘片上，因此它漂浮在盘片上方的薄薄一层空气中
And there's a read/write head at the very end that can sense the changes in the magnetic field that encode the bits
并且在最末端有一个读/写头，可以感知编码位的磁场变化
Okay so these platters are spinning around like counterclockwise like this, this arm can go back and forth
好的，所以这些盘子像逆时针一样旋转，这样的手臂可以前后移动
So there's a lot of mechanical gear so this is all mechanical
所以有很多机械装备，所以这都是机械装置
So the mechanical nature of a rotating disc
所以旋转盘的机械性质
Means it's going to be slower right then DRAMs and SRAMs
意味着它会比DRAM和SRAM慢
And there's also electronics like it's like a little computer in firmware
而且还有电子设备，就像固件中的一台小电脑一样
That that actually controls the operation of this drive that controls how this arm goes back and forth
这实际上控制了该驱动器的操作，该驱动器控制该臂如何来回移动
And and and controls how the data is read off of the the read/write head
并且和控制如何从读/写头读取数据
So just in a little more detail we can think of these disks consists of platters
因此，我们可以想到这些磁盘由盘片组成
Each platter has two surfaces the top and a bottom
每个盘片顶部和底部有两个表面
And then each surface consists of these trees are concentric rings  called tracks
然后每个表面由这些树组成的同心环称为轨道
And then each track consists of us it consists of sectors which contain the data
然后每个轨道由我们组成，它由包含数据的扇区组成
So typically 512,512 bits, oh I'm sorry bytes
所以通常512,512位，哦，对不起，字节
And then except these tracks are separated by gaps
然后除了这些轨道被间隙分开
That goat that these gaps like right here that don't contain data
那个山羊，这些差距就在这里，不包含数据
Now platters are aligned on top of each other on the spindle
现在盘片在主轴上彼此对齐
And so tracks that are aligned on the different surfaces
因此，在不同表面上对齐的轨道
Such as this track here on those the collection of those
比如这条轨道就在那些收集那些
Tracks form what we call a cylinder okay because it has a cylindrical shape
轨道形成我们所谓的圆柱形，因为它具有圆柱形状
Now the capacity of disks is that the number of bits that can be stored
现在磁盘的容量就是可以存储的位数
And vendors kind of they all dis vendors use they quote the capacity in gigabytes
他们所有供应商都使用他们引用容量为千兆字节的供应商
But where a gigabyte is 10^9 bytes right instead of 2^20,okay like like you would expect
但是，如果一个千兆字节是10 ^ 9字节而不是2 ^ 20，那么就像你期望的那样
So what...I'm not sure why they do this
那么......我不确定他们为什么这样做
But it allows by by quoting their capacity and gigabytes in 10^9 bytes
但它允许通过引用10 ^ 9字节的容量和千兆字节
It's a bigger number right
这是一个更大的数字
So it looks better it looks like there's more information
所以看起来好像有更多的信息
It's a little I don't really know why they do it but I think that's why it is
这有点我不知道为什么他们这样做但我认为这就是为什么
And it's one of those little bit annoying things that we just have to just  know about and get used to
这是我们必须了解并习惯的那些有点恼人的事情之一
Now the capacity is determined by 2 independent technology factors
现在容量由2个独立的技术因素决定
One is the recording density so that's how many bits can you pack into a single sector
一个是记录密度，因此你可以将多少位打包到一个扇区中
Or porous or at least a portion of a track
或多孔或至少一部分轨道
And then the track density which is sort of how close can you put those tracks together
然后是轨道密度，这是你将这些轨道放在一起的距离
And then the product of those two is what's called the areal density and that determines the overall capacity of the disc
然后这两者的产物就是所谓的面密度，它决定了光盘的整体容量
So the higher the areal capacity the more bits you can squeeze on to that onto that surface
因此，面积容量越大，你可以在该表面上挤压的位数就越多
Now in the old days when aerial densities were fairly low
现在，在过去，空中密度相当低
Each each track on the surface would have the same number of sectors
表面上的每个轨道将具有相同数量的扇区
Okay so there was a constant number of sectors per track
好的，所以每个轨道的扇区数量不变
So now what happens as you as your tracks go from the
所以现在发生了什么，因为你的轨道来自
You know near the whole by the spindle as they go as they move outward
当它们向外移动时，你知道它们在整个过程中靠近它们
Right if you have the same number of sectors with the same bit density
如果你具有相同数量的具有相同位密度的扇区，则正确
That the gaps between sectors are going to get bigger and bigger as you go out
当你外出时，各个部门之间的差距会变得越来越大
And you're going to be wasting more and more of your space
而且你将浪费越来越多的空间
So at when aerial densities were fairly low this was okay
因此，当空中密度相当低时，这是可以的
But after a while it just became not okay to waste that much room
但过了一段时间，浪费那么多空间就变得不合适了
So what modern systems do is they partition the tracks into these
所以现代系统所做的是将轨道划分为这些
So called rook recording zones
所谓的车记录区
Where each recording zone such as this right here
这里的每个记录区都在这里
Each recording zone has a consonant number of sectors
每个记录区域具有辅音数量的扇区
So each track in a recording zone has the same number of sectors
因此，记录区中的每个轨道具有相同数量的扇区
And of course as you move outward if you move outward in the recording zone
当然，如果你在记录区向外移动，你会向外移动
You're going to have bigger and bigger gaps
你将有越来越大的差距
But then you start a new recording zone
但是你开始一个新的录音区
That will have more sectors per track and then within that
那将是每个轨道更多的扇区，然后在其中
So you can see in this outer in this outer zone you have more you have more sectors
所以你可以在这个外部区域看到你有更多的扇区
Than you do on this inner zone
比你在这个内区做的
Okay so that's a way to kind of deal with that sort of that growth in the gaps to keep it from getting too large
好吧，这是一种处理差距增长的方法，以防止它变得太大
And so because we don't really have the number of sectors per track isn't constant
因此，因为我们并没有真正拥有每个轨道的扇区数量并不是一成不变的
We'll use an Average the average sectors per track across
我们将使用平均每个轨道的平均扇区
All recording zones when we do serve our capacity estimates
当我们提供容量估算时，所有记录区域
Okay so you can imagine the formula for computing the disk capacity is fairly straightforward
好的，你可以想象计算磁盘容量的公式是相当简单的
It's the number of bytes per sector
它是每个扇区的字节数
Times the average number of sectors per track
计算每个轨道的平均扇区数
Times the average number of tracks per surface times the number of surfaces per platter
将每个表面的平均轨道数乘以每个盘的表面数
Times the number of platters per disk okay
每盘磁盘数量好吧
Now let's look at how just work
现在让我们来看看它是如何工作的
So these these surfaces are spinning at a fixed rotational rate
因此，这些表面以固定的旋转速度旋转
Now a typical rate may be 7200 rpm s is a fairly common rotational rate
现在典型的速率可能是7200转/分钟，这是相当常见的转速
So the disc is spinning around you can see this pretty proud of that
所以光盘在旋转，你可以看到它为此感到自豪
So it's spinning around counter clockwise and then the arm
所以它逆时针转动，然后是手臂
Moves radially here we go
我们去的地方径向移动
The arm moves radially and it can go over any of the tracks
臂径向移动，可以越过任何轨道
Okay all right that's enough
好的，这就够了
Okay now when you have multiple platters
好的，现在你有多个拼盘
Each one of these each one of these there's actually multiple arms and there's a read/write head on each surface
这些中的每一个实际上都有多个臂，每个表面上都有一个读/写头
So if the platters has to - if - if each side of the platter
因此，如果拼盘必须 - 如果 - 如果 - 如果 - 拼盘的每一面
Is coated with this magnetic material then
然后涂上这种磁性材料
You'll have you have a read/write head on each side
你会在每一侧都有一个读/写头
And then these are all connected they kind of move together
然后这些都是连接在一起的
Now originally these these read/write heads would be they were rigid
现在最初这些读/写头将是僵硬的
Right because the densities tracked densities weren't that high
正确的原因是密度跟踪密度不是那么高
So they could they could just sort of licks and even though the tracks didn't align perfectly
因此，他们可以只是舔舔，即使轨道没有完美对齐
They could just sort of they could they could still cover
他们可能只是他们可以覆盖的那种
The read/write heads could still cover the tracks with these fixed  with these fixed arms
读/写磁头仍然可以用这些固定臂固定这些磁道
But nowadays that the densities are so high
但现在密度如此之高
That they actually the controller can actually move the read/write heads a little bit
他们实际上控制器实际上可以移动读/写头一点点
So that it matches up with that all of the tracks on all of the surfaces
这样它就匹配了所有表面上的所有轨道
Okay so let's look at how this works how we read data
好的，让我们看一下我们如何读取数据的方式
So we have our
所以我们有了
This is our this is our arm and the tip of the arrow is the read/write head
这是我们的这是我们的手臂，箭头的尖端是读/写头
And it's positioned and the platter is rotating counterclockwise
并且它被定位并且盘片逆时针旋转
And it's positioned just ready to read the blue sector
它的位置准备好阅读蓝色部门
So it as the blue sector spins underneath the read/write head
因此蓝色扇区在读/写头下旋转
It senses those bits and sends them up to the controller which passes them back up to the  the CPU
它会检测这些位并将它们发送到控制器，控制器将它们传递回CPU
And now the CPU is requested that the disk
现在CPU请求磁盘
It's requested the red data from the red sector
它要求红色部门的红色数据
So we have to take the controller takes that read/write head
所以我们必须把控制器带到读/写头
Moves it back to reds track
将其移回红色轨道
And then waits for it to spin around and
然后等待它旋转
And to the to the read/write head
并且到读/写头
And then it reads that that red that red sector
然后它读取红色那个红色扇区
Okay so when we first so there's really three components going on here that determine
好的，所以当我们第一次这样时，确实有三个组件在这里确定
How long it takes to read one of these sectors
阅读其中一个部门需要多长时间
The when we move the head that's called a seek
当我们移动被称为搜寻的头部时
When we waited for the red track to sort of rotate around
当我们等待红色轨道旋转时
That's called the rotational latency so however long it takes
这称为旋转延迟，因此需要很长时间
On average it will be half of the half of the time
平均而言，这将是半个时间的一半
It takes for the entire to circle all the way around
整个过程需要一路绕圈
And then there's the data transfer which is
然后是数据传输
Sort of how long it takes for that
这需要多长时间
For that track to pass under the read/write head
使该轨道在读/写头下通过
Now the reason the reason it's important to know this is that
现在知道这一点的重要性的原因是
These three components you add them together and that's the that's what your average
这三个组件将它们加在一起，这就是你的平均值
X time it takes to access data
X访问数据所需的时间
That time is dominated by the seek time
那段时间由寻道时间占主导地位
So seek times are measured in milliseconds right so we're moving this head there's
所以寻找时间是以毫秒为单位测量的，所以我们正在把这个头移到那里
This there's a servo that has to fire up and there's actual mechanical motion
这是一个必须启动的伺服系统和实际的机械运动
And that that takes time
这需要时间
And it's on the order of three to nine milliseconds and this has been true for decades
它大约在3到9毫秒之间，这已经存在了几十年
Right so this this value is not changing right
对，所以这个值没有改变
There's just sort of fundamental mechanical limits
这只是一种基本的机械限制
That make it very difficult to to decrease this this value
这使得降低这个值非常困难
Now the rotational latency
现在是旋转延迟
The time that it takes to spin around will we'll call that the t average rotation
旋转所需的时间我们称之为平均旋转
And then the time it takes to read the the bits will call t average transfer
然后，读取这些位所需的时间将调用t平均传输
Okay so we have t average seek which is this seek time rotational latency and transfer time
好的，所以我们有平均搜索，即寻道时间旋转延迟和传输时间
And now if we just take some typical numbers   and plug those in
现在，如果我们只是采取一些典型的数字并插入其中
You see that our seek time is on the order of milliseconds
你看，我们的寻道时间是毫秒级
The rotational rate is also on the order of milliseconds right
旋转速率也是毫秒级
So there's there's also mechanical limits and how fast you can you can spin these around
所以还有机械限制，你可以用多快的速度旋转它们
The access time and the transfer time  is very small
访问时间和传输时间非常短
So it's orders of magnitude smaller because you just have to read a few that the bits that are in one sector
所以它的数量级要小一些，因为你只需要阅读一些扇区中的位
Okay so if you look you can see that the total access time is dominated by seek  and rotational latency
好的，所以如果你看，你可以看到总访问时间主要是搜索和旋转延迟
So you know a good rule of thumb just for sort of estimating how long it takes to read from a disk
所以你知道一个好的经验法则，只是为了估计从磁盘读取所需的时间
It is just take twice the seek the seek time and you'll be pretty close
只需要两次寻找寻找时间，你就会非常接近
And basically the transfer time is you get that for free
基本上转移时间是你免费获得的
Now here's the here's the important thing to know about disks
现在，这里有关于磁盘的重要信息
We SRAM access times about four nanoseconds to get a double word
我们的SRAM访问时间大约为4纳秒，以获得双字
Dram is about 60 nanoseconds
Dram大约是60纳秒
So DRAM is about an order of magnitude slower than SRAM
所以DRAM比SRAM慢一个数量级
But disk is 40,000 times slower than SRAM
但是磁盘比SRAM慢40,000倍
So that's 4,000 orders of magnitude difference
这就是4,000个数量级的差异
That's huge and it's it's 250 times orders of magnitude slower than DRAMs
这是巨大的，它比DRAM慢250倍
So the there's a big gap between DRAM and SRAM
所以DRAM和SRAM之间存在很大差距
And there's an even bigger gap between disk and other memory types
磁盘和其他内存类型之间存在更大的差距
Now modern disks present a much simpler view
现在，现代磁盘呈现出更简单的视图
Than so we then this track cylinder sector geometry
那么我们就这样跟踪汽缸扇形几何形状
So modern modern disk controllers actually present
所以现代现代磁盘控制器实际存在
To the CPU they present the disk as a sequence of logical blocks
它们将磁盘作为一系列逻辑块提供给CPU
Where each block is is a multiple of a sector size
每个块是扇区大小的倍数
So this in simplest case a block is just a logical block is one sector
所以在最简单的情况下，块只是一个逻辑块就是一个扇区
And then blocks are numbered starting at zero
然后块从零开始编号
And they just go all the way up to some to some large number
他们只是一直到一些大的数字
And then the the disk controller keeps the mapping maintains the mapping between logical blocks
然后磁盘控制器保持映射保持逻辑块之间的映射
And the actual physical sectors
和实际的物理部门
So as in the old saying is you know most interesting ideas in computer science are involve some form of indirection
因此，在古语中你知道计算机科学中最有趣的想法涉及某种形式的间接
So this is a level of indirection
所以这是一个间接层面
That provides you know this mapping between logical blocks and physical blocks
这让你了解逻辑块和物理块之间的映射
So it allows disk controllers to take some cylinders and reserve them as spare cylinders
因此，它允许磁盘控制器采用一些气缸并将其保留为备用气缸
That aren't mapped in illogical blocks
这不是映射在不合逻辑的块中
And then if there's if one of the sectors goes bad in a cylinder
然后，如果有一个扇区在一个圆柱体中坏了
That the disk controller can just copy the data over to a spare cylinder and then just keep going right
磁盘控制器可以将数据复制到备用柱面，然后继续向右移动
So this is why your 4matic capacity is less than sort of the if you know if you counted the number of actual cylinders on the disk
因此，如果你知道是否计算了磁盘上实际气缸的数量，那么这就是你的4matic容量小于等级的原因
Your 4matic capacity is less than the maximum capacity
你的4matic容量小于最大容量
Because some of those cylinders are being reserved for failures
因为其中一些汽缸是为故障预留的
Now devices like disks are connected to the to the CPU and the memory
现在，像磁盘这样的设备连接到CPU和内存
Via the I/O bridge over another kind of bus called an I/O bus
通过I / O桥通过另一种称为I / O总线的总线
This what I'm showing you now is actually not representative of modern systems
我现在向你展示的内容实际上并不代表现代系统
It's representative of what was called the pci bus about five years ago
它代表了大约五年前所谓的pci总线
Modern buses now are the pci bus is a broadcast bus meaning it's just a single set of wires
现代公交车现在是pci总线是广播总线，这意味着它只是一组电线
So if any device us changes the values on those wires
因此，如果任何设备我们更改这些电线上的值
Every device on that bus can see those values
该总线上的每个设备都可以看到这些值
Okay that's called a broadcast bus and it's a simplest kind of way to hook things together
好的，它被称为广播总线，它是将事物连接在一起的最简单的方式
Modern systems use a bus structure called pci express
现代系统使用称为pci express的总线结构
Which although it has the word pci and it's completely different it's point-to-point
虽然它有pci这个词，但它是完全不同的，它是点对点的
So devices are connected by a set of point-to-point connections
因此，设备通过一组点对点连接进行连接
Arbitrated by a-- by some kind of a switch
由a--通过某种开关仲裁
And we won't go into it it's the same idea it it's a much more efficient design
我们不会进入它同样的想法，它是一个更有效的设计
It's much faster and but it provides the same capability mainly it just attaches up
它更快，但它提供相同的功能，主要是它附加
It allows you to attach all of your devices to your to your CPU
它允许你将所有设备连接到CPU
So just think of this bus as this sort of a single set of wires
因此，只需将此总线视为一组电线即可
Where each wire carries a bit
每根电线都带有一点
And every device attached to it can see all the values of all the wires
并且连接到它的每个设备都可以看到所有电线的所有值
And so it there's some devices that are just built it directly into the motherboard and they attach to the bus like
所以它有一些设备只是直接建在主板上，它们连接到总线上
You know disks have just plugged directly into sockets on a motherboard
你知道磁盘刚刚直接插入主板上的插槽
And you know your graphics adapter and the USB controller
而且你知道你的图形适配器和USB控制器
And then the system presents an interface
然后系统提供一个界面
So you can plug mouse things like mice and keyboards into the USB controller
因此，你可以将鼠标和键盘等鼠标插入USB控制器
And then there's expansion slots that allow you that are
然后有扩展插槽，允许你这样做
Connect to the wires in the in the bus that allow you to add other devices right
连接到总线中的电线，允许你正确添加其他设备
Maybe network you know if you want to put a network adapter there
如果你想在那里放一个网络适配器，也许你知道网络
Now what happens when we want to read a disk sector
现在当我们想要读取磁盘扇区时会发生什么
Well the CPU initiates this read by writing a triple
那么CPU通过编写三元组来启动此读取
So it writes three different values it writes a command like say read
所以它写了三个不同的值，它写了一个命令，比如说read
It writes a logical block number
它写入一个逻辑块号
So I want to read a logical block number
所以我想读一个逻辑块号
And I want to place the contents of that logical block at a certain address in memory
我想将该逻辑块的内容放在内存中的某个地址
Okay so it's a command logical block number in a memory address
好的，这是内存地址中的命令逻辑块号
The disk controller reads the whatever sector corresponds to that logical block
磁盘控制器读取与该逻辑块对应的任何扇区
So we'll assume that logical blocks are consists of one sector
所以我们假设逻辑块由一个扇区组成
And then it does this interesting thing it copies it takes control of the bus
然后它做了这个有趣的事情，它复制它控制总线
And it copies the data this is the disk controller now
它现在复制数据，这是磁盘控制器
Copies the data across the I/O bus through the I/O bridge and directly to main memory without ever notifying the CPU
通过I / O桥将数据复制到I / O总线，直接复制到主存储器，而无需通知CPU
So the CPU is completely oblivious to the fact that this transfer is going on
所以CPU完全忘记了这种传输正在进行的事实
And then once it's once its transfer the data to main memory
然后，一旦它将数据传输到主存储器
Then it notifies the CPU using this mechanism called an interrupt
然后它使用这种称为中断的机制通知CPU
So it actually asserts a pin on the the actual CPU chip itself
所以它实际上在实际CPU芯片本身上声明了一个引脚
So it it changes the value of that pin from 0 to 1
所以它将该引脚的值从0更改为1
And that trigger is an interrupt and which notifies the CPU that sector has been copy
该触发器是一个中断，它通知CPU该扇区已被复制
Ok so then the CPU if there's some program somewhere waiting for that data to be read into memory
好的，那么CPU是否有某个程序在某处等待将数据读入内存
So now now the CPU can can execute that program and deal with that memory
所以现在CPU现在可以执行该程序并处理该内存
So what this what this mechanism allows
那么这个机制允许什么呢
And the reason they do this is because disks are just so god-awful slow
他们这样做的原因是因为磁盘太慢而且非常糟糕
The within 10 milliseconds a system could be executing millions and millions of instructions
在10毫秒内，系统可以执行数百万条指令
The CPU could be executing millions and millions of instructions
CPU可能正在执行数百万条指令
It will be a terrible waste if the CPU waited for that data to come off the disk
如果CPU等待数据从磁盘上脱落，那将是一个可怕的浪费
So what it does is it it issues this request to the disk controller
它的作用是它将此请求发送给磁盘控制器
And then while that well that really slow laborious process is going on
然后，虽然那个真正缓慢繁重过程的井正在进行中
The CPU can be executing other instructions and doing other useful work
CPU可以执行其他指令并执行其他有用的工作
So this is really essential to just sort of getting reasonable performance
所以这对于获得合理的性能非常重要
And from keeping this really slow disk system from slowing the system down
从保持这个非常慢的磁盘系统减慢系统速度
Now there's another interesting hype kind of disk called a solid-state disk
现在有另一个有趣的炒作类型的磁盘称为固态磁盘
Which is kind of halfway between rotating and rotating discs  and DRAM memories
这是旋转和旋转光盘与DRAM存储器之间的中间点
In a solid-state disk to the to the CPU
在一个固态磁盘到CPU
It looks exactly like a rotating disk it has the same socket plug
它看起来与旋转磁盘完全相同，它具有相同的插座插头
It has the same physical interface that has the same packaging
它具有相同的物理接口，具有相同的包装
It looks like a rotating disc
它看起来像一个旋转的圆盘
But instead of having all these mechanical parts it's actually built entirely out of flash memory
但它没有拥有所有这些机械部件，而是完全由闪存构建
And firmware that acts as the the controller
和充当控制器的固件
So inside of a solid-state disk there's a firmware a set of firmware called the flash translation layer
因此，在固态磁盘内部有一组固件，称为闪存转换层
Which serves the purpose as the same purpose as the disk controller does in a rotating disk d
其目的与磁盘控制器在旋转磁盘中的作用相同
And then the memory itself the read
然后记忆本身就读了
Data can be read read and written from the flash memory in units of pages
可以以页为单位从闪存读取和写入数据
Which depending on the technology can be 512 kbytes to 4 k bytes
这取决于技术可以是512千字节到4千字节
And then a sequence of pages forms a block
然后一系列页面形成一个块
Now these these these blocks are different from the logical blocks that the CPU does
现在这些这些块与CPU所做的逻辑块不同
So it's kind of an unfortunate overlap of terms
所以这是一个不幸的术语重叠
But the the trick is or the I guess the limitation is that data is written in units of pages
但诀窍是，或者我猜限制是数据是以页为单位写的
But a page can only be written after the entire block has been erased
但是只有在整个块被擦除后才能写入页面
Okay so that's that seems kind of weird but that's that's the way it works
好的，这似乎有点奇怪，但这就是它的工作方式
So what that means is if you want to write
那么这意味着你想要写作
If you want to write to a page you have to find a block somewhere that's been erased
如果你想写一个页面，你必须找到一个被删除的块
You have to copy all of the other pages in your target block over to that new block and then you can do the right
你必须将目标块中的所有其他页面复制到该新块，然后才能正确执行
Okay so you can see that rights now become fairly complex operation reads you can read anything
好的，你可以看到权利现在变得相当复杂，操作读取你可以阅读任何东西
And then like all flash a so it's kind of an efficient right because you're writing one page
然后像所有闪光一样，这是一种有效的权利，因为你正在写一页
But to do that you have to sort of copy all the other pages in it block and you have to erase the whole
但要做到这一点，你必须复制其中的所有其他页面块，你必须擦除整体
And then when you finish then you erase this block so it can be used for for other writes yes
然后当你完成后，你擦除这个块，以便它可以用于其他写入是
So eventually after a hundred thousand repeated writes these we're out
所以最终在经过十万次重复写入后，我们就出局了
Now the flash translation layer xin modern systems
现在闪现翻译层xin现代系统
Do all kinds of fancy proprietary algorithms to sort of extend the life they use caching
做各种花哨的专有算法，以延长他们使用缓存的生命
And and various tricks to extend the life of these SSD
并且还有各种技巧来延长这些SSD的使用寿命
So in practice it's not really a problem which I'll show you in a second
所以在实践中，这不是一个我会在一秒钟内告诉你的问题
So the performance characteristics of SSDs
所以SSD的性能特点
Now you can think of a typical hard drive you might be able to get
现在你可以想到一个典型的硬盘你可能会得到
You know I mean what if when I measure them when I measure my drives
你知道我的意思是当我测量我的驱动器时测量它们
I maybe forty fifty megabytes per second that would be a typical rate
我可能是每秒四十五十兆字节，这是一个典型的速度
Okay these SSDs are 10 times faster than that
好吧，这些SSD的速度要快10倍
So for sequential reads you can get about 500 50 megabytes
因此对于顺序读取，你可以获得大约500 50兆字节
Sequential writes are a little bit slower
顺序写入有点慢
Random access whether you're reading or writing is a little bit slower than sequential access
无论你是在阅读还是写作，随机访问都比顺序访问慢一点
And as we'll see this is that this is fairly common
而且我们会看到这是相当普遍的
It's it's in memory systems it's almost always better to do things sequentially  than to jump around
就是在内存系统中，按顺序执行操作几乎总是比跳转更好
And erasing random writes are slower because erase erasing takes about a millisecond right
擦除随机写入速度较慢，因为擦除擦除需要大约一毫秒的时间
So now we're back up to that that millisecond range which is which is slow
所以现在我们又回到那个毫秒级的范围，这个范围很慢
And as I mentioned yet if you modify one one one page after all the other pages in that block have to be copy
正如我所提到的那样，如果你在该块中的所有其他页面都必须复制之后修改一页
Now earlier SSDs had a huge gap between random writes and sequential reads
现在早期的SSD在随机写入和顺序读取之间存在巨大差距
But they because of sort of improvements in the flash translation layer
但是他们因为闪存翻译层的改进
These aren't really that that difference right reading and writing it's it's writing is slower
这些差异并不是正确的阅读和写作，它的写作速度较慢
But they're doing all kinds of interesting amazing things to get these numbers fairly close
但他们正在做各种有趣的惊人事情，以使这些数字相当接近
Ok so art when we have a model of SSDs we really don't need to distinguish anymore that between reads and writes
好吧，如果我们有一个SSD模型，我们真的不需要再区分读写
You okay so SSDs because they have no moving parts
你没关系SSD，因为它们没有活动部件
They're faster they take less power they're more rugged
他们的动力越来越快，他们的动力越来越大
You know which is why they're good for thumb drives
你知道为什么它们对拇指驱动器有好处
And you know ipods and things like that
你知道ipods和类似的东西
But they have this potential to wear out
但他们有可能磨损
Which could be a problem but in practice it's not for example
这可能是一个问题，但在实践中，它不是例如
Intel guarantees that you can do 128 petabytes of writes
英特尔保证你可以执行128 PB的写入
Before your SSD is no longer good
在你的SSD不再好之前
So that's a lot of data to write I mean think about how many years it would take to write that much data
所以要编写大量数据我的意思是考虑编写那么多数据需要多少年
And as of 2015 as of now
截至2015年截至目前
They're a lot more expensive per byte than rotating disks
它们每个字节比旋转磁盘贵很多
So rotating disks are much bigger but they're slower
所以旋转磁盘要大得多，但速度要慢一些
SSDs are smaller and faster
SSD更小更快
Now if you take
现在，如果你采取
If you look at the performance characteristics of these different storage devices relative to CPU
如果你看一下这些不同存储设备相对于CPU的性能特征
Over time you get this really interesting graph
随着时间的推移，你会得到这个非常有趣
Now this graph shows on the y-axis access time in nanoseconds  or in a log scale
现在，此图显示y轴访问时间，单位为纳秒或对数刻度
Okay so each one of these each change in units from 1,000 to 10,000 represents a order of magnitude difference in access time
好的，所以这些中的每一个都以1,000到10,000的单位变化表示访问时间的一个数量级差异
On the x-axis I've plotted time going from 1985 to 2015
在x轴上，我绘制了从1985年到2015年的时间
And then I've plotted the sort of the the access time or the cycle time of
然后我绘制了访问时间或周期时间的类型
The access time of the these devices disk SSD DRAM and SRAM
这些设备的访问时间是SSD SSD和SRAM
And the cycle time of processors
和处理器的循环时间
So let's look at on the bottom we have the the cycle time of processors over time
那么让我们看一下底部我们有处理器的循环时间随着时间的推移
And what you see is it's going down at is this sort of exponential rate  from 1985 to 2003
而你所看到的是它正在下降的是从1985年到2003年的这种指数速度
There's the doubling basically every 18 months or two years in clock frequency and a resulting
基本上每18个月或两年的时钟频率加倍，结果是
Halving of the cycle time over this 18-month two to two year period
在这18个月的两到两年期间，将周期时间减半
So this so what what manufacturers did until 2003
所以这就是制造商在2003年之前所做的事情
To make their processors faster was a but they would just double the clock frequency
为了使他们的处理器更快，他们只会使时钟频率加倍
They decrease the feature size of the chips that they were making
它们减小了它们制造的芯片的特征尺寸
And that would allow them to put things closer together
这将使他们能够把事情放在一起
And then have that and then increase the clock frequency by a proportional amount
然后有那个，然后按比例增加时钟频率
Now this all ended 2003 was an interesting year in computer history
现在这一切都在2003年结束，这是计算机历史上有趣的一年
Because of this there's a sort of unfortunate property that the power that you consume
因此，你所消耗的能量有一种不幸的特性
Is proportional to your frequency
与你的频率成正比
Okay so the more power I mean the higher the frequency the more power you consume
好的，所以我的意思越强，频率越高，消耗的功率越大
By 2003 the processor that Intel was getting ready to ship was going to burn about 800 watts of power
到2003年，英特尔准备出货的处理器将耗费大约800瓦的功率
Think about 800 watt light bulbs inside your laptop and
想想你的笔记本电脑里面有800瓦的灯泡
I actually saw an early prototype of one of these devices
我实际上看到了其中一个设备的早期原型
And the the heatsink to absorb the power from the chip was about this big it was about four square inches
从芯片吸收功率的散热器大约是四平方英寸
It's a giant thing just sitting on the motherboard
这只是坐在主板上的一件大事
So that's what we what we say is that processor design hit the power wall in 2003
所以我们所说的就是处理器设计在2003年触及了电源墙
They could no longer just continue to increase clock frequencies
他们再也不能继续增加时钟频率
To to get faster to make faster computers
为了更快地制作更快的计算机
And what so what they had to do after 2003
那么他们在2003年之后必须做些什么
Instead of increasing the clock frequency and try and set up doubling the clock frequency
而不是增加时钟频率，并尝试设置加倍时钟频率
They put more processor cores onto the chips
他们在芯片上放置了更多处理器内核
So now they subdivided a CPU chip into individual processor cores
所以现在他们将CPU芯片细分为单独的处理器内核
Each one could execute its own instructions
每个人都可以执行自己的指令
And then so and by running in parallel
然后通过并行运行
You could do more effective work so the effective cycle time could continue to go down
你可以做更有效的工作，因此有效的周期时间可能会继续下降
So what I've what I plotted here on the bottom is the effective cycle time
所以我在底部绘制的是有效循环时间
So basically the the cycle time divided by the number of cores
所以基本上循环时间除以核心数
So here in 2005 that the first systems use two cores
所以在2005年，第一个系统使用两个核心
So now you can run two independent threads or two independent programs
所以现在你可以运行两个独立的线程或两个独立的程序
And currently it's about four cores server class systems you can get eight cores
目前，它是关于四核服务器级系统，你可以获得八个核心
And there's even some 12 core chips
甚至还有12个核心芯片
So in the future what's going to happen is that the the clock frequencies are going to stay fairly constant
因此，未来将要发生的是时钟频率将保持相当稳定
So you can see the site you can see the the cycle times are
所以你可以看到你可以看到周期时间的站点
They actually increased a little bit here and then they're slowly going down but it's generally flat
它们实际上在这里增加了一点，然后它们慢慢地下降但是它通常是平的
And so the only way to really get more performance
这是真正获得更多性能的唯一途径
Go forward is to increase the number of independent course
前进是增加独立课程的数量
And that's just that's just the way it's got to be
而这就是它的方式
Now here in the the black circle the second line I've plotted the access time for SRAM over time
现在，在第二行的黑色圆圈中，我绘制了SRAM随时间的访问时间
And you can see that SRAM is tracking CPU pretty good
你可以看到SRAM跟踪CPU非常好
And it and there's it's it's an order of magnitude slower but
而它和它的速度要慢一些
It's tracking the CPU performance pretty well
它很好地跟踪CPU性能
Dram you can see there's a huge gap between the CPU and the DRAM several orders of magnitude
Dram你可以看到CPU和DRAM之间存在几个数量级的巨大差距
And in the last few years DRAMs have gotten a little better
在过去的几年里，DRAM已经变得更好了
But they've proven surprisingly difficult to to make faster
但他们已经证明难以加快速度
SSDs are kind of in between disks and DRAM
SSD介于磁盘和DRAM之间
And then disks up here you can see at a million nanoseconds that's the that's a millisecond
然后在这里的磁盘你可以看到一百万纳秒就是那个毫秒
So you can see disks are sort of in this in this sort of millisecond range with access times
因此，你可以看到磁盘在这种毫秒范围内具有访问时间
And those those that they've gone down a little bit but not really too much
而那些那些他们已经下降了一点但不是真的太多了
So the point I want to make is that there's this huge gap between DRAM  SSD disk in and CPUs
所以我想说的是DRAM SSD磁盘和CPU之间存在巨大差距
And in some cases it's even getting worse as time goes by so that's a problem right how
而且在某些情况下，随着时间的推移，它甚至会变得越来越糟，因此这是一个问题
Our programs all need data our data is stored in memory and disk
我们的程序都需要数据，我们的数据存储在内存和磁盘中
So if if our if our computers are getting faster
所以如果你的计算机变得越来越快
And our storage devices are are staying relatively the same or relatively slower
我们的存储设备保持相对相同或相对较慢
Then we've got a problem right increases in in our in computer performance won't
然后我们遇到了一个问题，在我们的计算机性能上不会增加
It'll be hard to make our programs run faster
让我们的程序运行得更快很难
Because we'll be limited by the time it takes to to access the data
因为我们会受到访问数据所需时间的限制
Ok so that's that that's sort of the fundamental problem that we have to deal with
好的，这就是我们必须处理的基本问题
And it turns out that the key to bridging this this gap between the CPU and and memory
事实证明，这是弥合CPU和内存之间差距的关键
Is this is this very basic fundamental property of programs called locality
这是地方性程序的这个非常基本的基本属性
Okay and so this is an essential sort of fundamental enduring property of programs
好的，所以这是程序的一个基本的持久性财产
So we say that so programs have this property called locality
所以我们说所以程序有这个属性叫做locality
And what this means is that
这意味着什么
I'm sorry I'll just I have to read it because it's it's really accurate definition
对不起，我只需要阅读它，因为这是非常准确的定义
So programs tend to use data and instructions whose addresses are near or equal to those that they have used recently
因此，程序倾向于使用其地址接近或等于最近使用的数据和指令
Okay so if a program access is a data item the chances are very high
好的，如果程序访问是一个数据项，那么机会非常高
That it's going to access that data item or a nearby data item sometime in the near future
它将在不久的将来某个时间访问该数据项或附近的数据项
Okay that likelihood that the program is going to access that data item or a nearby a data item
好的，该程序可能会访问该数据项或附近的数据项
In the near future is that is this property called locality
在不久的将来，这个属性称为地方
So well does we just typically distinguish two two different kinds of locality
我们通常只能区分两种不同的地方
Temporal locality is the property that recently referenced items are likely to be referenced again in the near future
时间局部性是最近引用的项目可能在不久的将来再次被引用的属性
Kaycee 50 so if you read a variable
如果你读了变量，凯赛50就这样了
Chances are you're going to read that variable again
你有可能再次阅读该变量
For example suppose you're summing into a variable inside of a loop
例如，假设你在循环内汇总为变量
Each loop iteration you're going to access that that variable okay
你将要访问该变量的每个循环迭代都可以
Spatial locality is that the tendency for items with nearby addresses up that
空间局部性是指具有附近地址的物品的趋势
That items if we access if we access one item chances are high we're going to access a nearby item
如果我们访问，如果我们访问一个项目的机会很高，我们将访问附近的项目
Okay so let's look at this little snippet of code and see if we can identify all the different kinds of locality in this code
好的，让我们看看这段代码片段，看看我们是否可以在此代码中识别出所有不同类型的局部性
So we have two different kinds of of references there's data references
所以我们有两种不同类型的参考资料
And then there's instructions right so we're reading instructions out of memory
然后是正确的指示，所以我们正在读取内存中的指令
And those instructions are referencing data okay
这些说明正好引用数据
So first of all notice that we're we're referencing the elements of an array in succession
首先要注意的是，我们正在连续引用数组的元素
So we're increasing I by one each time and then we're
所以我们每次增加一个然后我们就是
So we're incrementing I through the loop and we're reading a[i]
所以我们通过循环增加我，我们正在阅读[i]
Okay so this is called a stride one reference pattern the
好的，所以这被称为一个步幅参考模式
The stride is how much we're incrementing this this index
大步是我们将这个指数递增多少
So we're since we're incrementing it by one we call that a stride one pattern
因此，我们将它增加一个，我们称之为一个跨步的模式
So what kind of what kind of locality is the these repeated references to a[i] spatial or temporal
那么，对于[i]空间或时间的这些重复引用，究竟是什么类型的局部性
That spatial right because we're accessing nearby items
那个空间权利因为我们正在访问附近的物品
Okay what about the referencing this this variable some inside the loop
好的，在循环内部引用这个变量
That's temporal
这是暂时的
Now what about instructions
现在说明怎么样
So we're referencing where each loop iteration where reference we're executing a sequence of instructions
所以我们引用每个循环迭代的位置，其中引用我们正在执行一系列指令
So what kind of locality is that
那是什么样的地方
Within each loop iteration? no that's spatial right
在每个循环迭代中？没有空间权利
Because we're just executing a sequence of instructions within each loop iteration
因为我们只是在每次循环迭代中执行一系列指令
But then we cycle through the loop repeatedly
但是我们反复循环循环
So we'll chances so each loop iteration we're going to access each of those instructions
因此，我们很有可能每次循环迭代，我们将访问每个指令
That we access the previous loop iteration right
我们正确访问前一个循环迭代
So we go up we just keep at we're just going to keep executing the sum
所以我们上去，我们只是继续我们只是继续执行总和
Assembly language instructions that implement this loop body
实现此循环体的汇编语言指令
Now in this simple example it's probably this one instruction
现在在这个简单的例子中，它可能就是这一条指令
But in general your loop can have multiple instructions
但一般来说，你的循环可以有多个指令
Now when I claim to you I'm one of the one of the main sort of points of this just this whole course
现在，当我向你宣称时，我就是这整个课程的主要观点之一
Is that as a professional programmer
这是一个专业的程序员
It's an essential skill that that you be able to look at code and so get a qualitative sense of its locality
这是一项必不可少的技能，你可以查看代码，从而获得对其本地性的定性认识
Because as we'll see good locality turns into good performance
因为我们会看到好的地方变成了良好的表现
The way that systems are built these days
这些天系统的构建方式
So as a programmer it's very important for you to be able to kind of look at code and get some qualitative sense
因此，作为一名程序员，能够看到代码并获得一些定性意义对你来说非常重要
Like yeah that's pretty good locality that's terrible locality right that that's
就像是的，这是非常好的地方，这是可怕的地方，那就是
And what you want to do is avoid the terrible locality in your code
你想要做的是避免代码中的可怕局部性
So let's look at a simple example here
那么让我们看一个简单的例子吧
To see what I mean by this
看看我的意思
So what I'm doing is I'm taking an array a two-dimensional array a
所以我正在做的是我将一个数组作为一个二维数组a
With m m rows and n columns
m m行和n列
And within it a doubly nested loop iterating on I and j
并且在其中迭代I和j的双重嵌套循环
I'm summing the elements of that array
我正在总结该数组的元素
Okay seems this a very simple operation what could go wrong right
好吧，这似乎是一个非常简单的操作，可能会出错
So it turns out if you write this code to have bad locality  it will run order magnitude slower
因此，如果你编写此代码以使其具有较差的局部性，则它将以较慢的顺序运行
Okay so if just look at this if you look at this do you think this has good locality or bad locality
好吧，如果只看这个，如果你看这个，你认为这有好的地方或糟糕的地方
Let's look at the with respect to the accesses of a
让我们看一下关于a的访问
Good or bad ?
是好是坏 ？
Well so how is how is a laid out in memory right
那么如何在记忆中如何正确布局呢
It's row wise all right so see uses used lays out a raised row wise
这是行的明智，所以看到使用的用法列出了一个明智的行
So the first all the elements of the first row followed by all the elements
所以第一行的第一个元素后跟所有元素
Of the second row followed by all the elements of the third row
在第二行之后是第三行的所有元素
Okay so how are we accessing this array
好的，我们如何访问这个数组
Look at we're accessing a[i][j] and we're varying j the fastest
看看我们正在访问[i] [j]，我们正在以最快的速度改变j
So we hold I constant and then we vary j
所以我们保持不变，然后我们改变j
And then we access all so we hold the I constant to access row i
然后我们访问所有，所以我们保持I常量访问第i行
And then we vary j to access all the columns in that row
然后我们改变j来访问该行中的所有列
Okay so each each hitter and then we increase and then we go back and increase i
好的，所以每个击球手然后我们增加然后我们回去增加我
So now we're accessing the next row
所以现在我们正在访问下一行
Okay so if we were to look at the addresses of a[i][j] the sequence of addresses  that are being read
好的，如果我们要查看[i] [j]的地址，正在读取的地址序列
Those would correspond to a stride one access and so we'd be accessing all the elements of a sequentially in order
那些将对应于步幅一次访问，因此我们将依次按顺序访问所有元素
Okay so that's really good spatial locality right that's the best you can do
好吧，这是非常好的空间位置，这是你能做的最好的
Now what about what about and then we have temporal locality on some so that's good
现在怎么样，然后我们有一些时间局部性，所以这是好的
Right so everything about this is pretty good so this is the good case
对，所以关于这一切的一切都很好，所以这是好的情况
Now what about this what I've done I've taken the same program
那么我做了什么我采取了同样的计划
And I've just inverted the loops so it's a loop on j first and then on i
我只是颠倒了循环，所以它首先在j上循环，然后在i上循环
And then I just have the same inner loop body
然后我只有相同的内部循环体
Now what does that do to this what does that do to the spatial locality of our accesses okay
现在，这对我们访问的空间局部性做了什么呢？
Yes
是
Terrible because it's going you should be offended what do you see this isn't lawful
可怕的是因为它会让你感到冒犯你认为这不合法
But it's terrible right because look it
但这很糟糕，因为看起来
So we're now we're holding j
所以我们现在正拿着j
We're holding j constant and then we're iterating through the jt element of each row so that's skipping
我们保持j不变，然后我们遍历每一行的jt元素，以便跳过
We have n we have n elements in each row so we're doing a stride n access through memory
我们在每行中都有n个元素，因此我们通过内存进行了大步访问
So we're going like this
所以我们就是这样
And then we're incrementing then we're looking then we're incrementing the column by one and then we're doing this again
然后我们正在递增然后我们正在寻找然后我们将列递增1然后我们再次这样做
So it's terrible spatial locality this is the worst spatial locality we could get
所以这是一个糟糕的空间局部性，这是我们可以获得的最差的空间局部性
Now let's look at a three dimensional array
现在让我们来看一个三维数组
And let me ask you that let me post the following question
让我问你，让我发布以下问题
Can you based on this sort of qualitative idea that
你能否基于这种定性观念
This idea that you want you want to try to get a stride one reference pattern
这个想法，你希望你想尝试获得一个步骤参考模式
Okay so how would you permute these given this given this inner body
好吧那么鉴于这个内在的身体，你会如何置换这些呢？
A[k][i][j] how would you promote that permute these these loop indices to give stride one reference pattern
A [k] [i] [j]你如何促进这些循环索引的置换，以给出一个参考模式
Okay that's right kij is right
好吧，这是正确的kij是对的
So what in general we want to do is we want to go going from right to left
所以我们通常想做的是我们想要从右到左
We want we want those indices to be changing the fastest
我们希望我们希望这些指数变化最快
So we want j we want k and I to be held constant and then we want to change j
所以我们想要j我们希望k和I保持不变然后我们想要改变j
Then we want to increment I and then for that value that those values of k and i
然后我们想要增加I然后为该值增加k和i的那些值
We want to want to sequence through all the the values of j again
我们想要再次排序j的所有值
Okay
好的
Okay so we've looked at properties of technology of storage technologies
好的，我们已经研究了存储技术的技术属性
And well we and there's this sort of basic sort of fundamental principle that cheaper storage
而且我们还有这种基本原则，即更便宜的存储
You bigger storage higher capacity storage is cheaper
你存储容量越大，存储容量越大越便宜
More expensive storage is smaller
更昂贵的存储空间更小
Because we just don't have that we don't we can't spend enough money
因为我们没有那个我们没有，我们不能花足够的钱
There's this gap there's this gap between our storage devices and the CPU
我们的存储设备和CPU之间存在这种差距
That is in at least in the case of disks are getting bigger
至少在磁盘越来越大的情况下
And we have programs that exhibit locality
我们有展示地方的计划
Okay so these three things these properties of storage technologies
好的，这三件事就是存储技术的这些特性
And properties of our programs
和我们的程序的属性
Complement each other in this beautiful way to suggest and inform the design of our storage systems
以这种美丽的方式相互补充，为我们的存储系统的设计提供建议和信息
And this design is something called a memory hierarchy
这种设计称为内存层次结构
Okay here's the idea of a memory hierarchy
好的，这是内存层次结构的想法
You layer instead of a flat memory system you now
你现在分层而不是平面内存系统
You create your memory system as a hierarchy of devices
你将内存系统创建为设备层次结构
And at the top of the at the top of this hierarchy
并位于此层次结构顶部的顶部
You have your smaller faster and more expensive storage devices
你拥有更小，更快，更昂贵的存储设备
So at the very top you have registers
所以在最顶层你有寄存器
Which are which can be accessed and within one cycle right one instruction
哪一个可以访问，并在一个周期内正确的一条指令
While that instructions executing can access read and write into a register
执行指令时可以访问读写寄存器
Okay so registers are at the top of the hierarchy
好的，所以寄存器位于层次结构的顶部
But because those are in custom silicon they're very expensive right
但由于这些都是定制芯片，因此它们非常昂贵
The fabrication plants to make processors cost billions of dollars
制造处理器的制造工厂耗资数十亿美元
Okay so this is the most expensive and
好的，所以这是最贵的
Because of that it's also the smallest we've only got 16 registers at the top of the hierarchy
因为它也是最小的，我们在层次结构的顶部只有16个寄存器
Now below that we put one or more SRAM memories remember SRAM is faster
现在，我们把一个或多个SRAM存储器记得SRAM更快
It's the fastest kind of memory
这是最快的记忆
So we put one or more so-called caches cache memories built out of SRAM
因此我们将一个或多个所谓的高速缓存存储器建立在SRAM之外
In the processor chip itself
在处理器芯片本身
And then and these caches because they're made out of SRAM they're on the order of megabytes in size
然后和这些缓存，因为它们是由SRAM制成的，它们的大小是兆字节
Okay they're much bigger than registers but they're they're megabytes
好吧，它们比寄存器大得多，但它们只是兆字节
Okay which if we look and then beneath that is our
好吧，如果我们看起来然后在那之下就是我们的
Main memory which is built out of DRAMs and those can be gigabytes  tens of gigabytes on modern systems
在DRAM中构建的主存储器在现代系统上可以是几十亿字节
And then below that is our local disks
然后在我们的本地磁盘下面
And we can even have lower layers like web servers that are storing you know for storing stuff on google
而且我们甚至可以拥有像网络服务器这样的较低层，存储你知道在谷歌上存储的东西
That you can think of that as just part of our our hierarchy
你可以将其视为我们层次结构的一部分
Now here's the here's the key idea and a higher in a in a memory hierarchy
现在这里是关键想法，在内存层次结构中更高
Each level in this hierarchy holds data that's retrieved from the next lower level
此层次结构中的每个级别都包含从下一个较低级别检索的数据
Okay so caches hold registers hold data that's that's stored in the l1 cache
好的，所以高速缓存保持寄存器保存数据，这些数据存储在l1高速缓存中
The l1 cache holds data that's retrieved from the l2 cache the l3 cache holds data  that's restored
l1缓存保存从l2缓存中检索的数据，l3缓存保存已恢复的数据
That's that's retrieved from main memory main memory holds data that's retrieved from secondary disk and so on
从主内存主内存中检索到的内容包含从辅助磁盘检索的数据，依此类推
Now as we'll see the that the reason memory systems are designed like this
现在，我们将看到内存系统设计如此的原因
Is that they when you have this kind of system
当你拥有这种系统时就是他们
This you can access in general you can access your data at the speed of the fastest item in the day
你可以访问这一点，你可以以当天最快项目的速度访问你的数据
And at the top of the hierarchy
在层次结构的顶部
So that's the fastest
所以这是最快的
But with the cost of the storage at the lower part of the hierarchy
但是在层次结构的较低部分存储的成本
Okay so this this works all because of an idea called caching
好的，所以这一切都有效，因为一个叫做缓存的想法
So a cache and compete to took to a computer scientist is a
所以缓存和竞争对计算机科学家是一个
It's a smaller faster storage device that acts as a staging area for the data and a larger slower device
它是一个更小的更快的存储设备，充当数据的暂存区域和更慢的设备
So just like like here you can think of your main memory is a cache for data
所以就像在这里一样，你可以想到你的主内存是数据缓存
That's stored on disk right you read memory from disk and then you store it in main memory
这是存储在磁盘上的，你从磁盘读取内存然后将其存储在主内存中
Okay you can think of the main memory as a staging area
好吧，你可以把主存储器想象成一个临时区域
So once you get the data from the disk you don't access it again on the disk you access it in memory which is much faster
因此，一旦从磁盘获取数据，就不会再在磁盘上访问它，而是在内存中访问它，速度要快得多
Ok so this idea propagates all the way up the hierarchy
好的，这个想法一直在层次结构中传播
Okay so we you can think of a cache on
好的，我们你可以想到一个缓存
One way to think of a cache is imagine your backpack when you're getting ready to come to school in the morning
考虑缓存的一种方法是想象你的背包，当你准备早上来学校
So you're in your apartment which is kind of far away from school
所以你在你的公寓里有点远离学校
So before you come into school you take items from from your house
所以在你上学之前，你要从你的房子里拿走物品
And you put them in your backpack right
你把它们放在你的背包里吧
Then you come to school if you need those items you get there in your backpack
如果你需要那些放在背包里的东西，你就来学校
You know if you didn't do that
你知道，如果你不这样做
Every time you needed something you'd have to walk back home and get it  and then walk back to school
每次你需要的东西，你必须走回家并获得它，然后走回学校
All right so it's so the idea of caching is very you know it's a very familiar kind of simple notion
好吧所以这就是缓存的想法，你知道它是一种非常熟悉的简单概念
But it turns out to be quite powerful and it shows up in all parts of computer systems
但事实证明它非常强大，并且它出现在计算机系统的所有部分中
Okay so so what we say is that for each level k in the hierarchy
好的，我们所说的是对于层次结构中的每个级别k
The the faster smaller device at level k serves as a cache
级别k中较小的较小设备用作缓存
For the larger slower device at level k+1
对于k + 1级较大的较慢设备
And remember our our levels go from so l0 is the highest
并且记住我们的水平从那以后l0是最高的
So this the smallest lowest level is actually the highest
所以这个最小的最低级别实际上是最高的
The further step in the cat in the hierarchy and as we increase the levels
层次结构中cat的进一步步骤以及我们提高级别的步骤
We're going down the hierarchy
我们正在走下层次结构
Now why do they work so this is this is a really fundamental idea
现在他们为什么这么做，所以这是一个非常基本的想法
They work because of locality
他们因地方而工作
So because of locality programs tend to access data that's stored at level k
因此，由于地点性，程序倾向于访问存储在级别k的数据
More often than they access data at level k+1 o
通常比访问k + 1 o级的数据更常见
Okay so if we access an item at level +1
好的，如果我们访问级别为+1的项目
We can move it up to level k chances are because of locality we're going to access it again
我们可以将它提升到k级机会，因为我们将再次访问它
Okay so now we're accessing the data at level k multiple times at the rate at the speed of love
好的，现在我们以爱的速度多次访问k级数据
Okay not at the speed of level k plus one okay so that's
好吧，不是以k级加一个好的速度，所以那就是
That's the fun the fundal fundamental idea
这是基金基本理念的乐趣
And because we're not accessing data at level +1 as often
而且因为我们不经常访问+1级数据
We can afford to use slower storage devices which are cheaper
我们可以负担得起使用更便宜的速度较慢的存储设备
In this and thus we can make them bigger and cheaper per gig
在这方面，因此我们可以使它们更大，更便宜
So what this does is the hierarchy creates a a large pool of storage
这样做的是层次结构创建了一个大型存储池
That's roughly about the size of the lowest level
这大致是最低级别的大小
That can be accessed at the speed at the highest level
可以以最高级别的速度访问
All right let's let's look at how caching works in a general way
好吧让我们来看看缓存如何以一般方式工作
And then we'll see on thursday how these hardware cache memories work
然后我们将在星期四看到这些硬件缓存如何工作
Okay but like I said caching is a very general idea that can be applied at all levels in the hierarchy
好吧，但就像我说的，缓存是一个非常通用的想法，可以应用于层次结构中的所有级别
So here we have a cache - so the in all kinds of most caches there's some kind of transfer unit
所以这里我们有一个缓存 - 所以在各种大多数缓存中都有某种传输单元
To go from one level to the next
从一个级别到下一个级别
So here we have at this at this upper level
所以我们在这个上层有这个
We have a what we'll call the cache that can hold four blocks
我们有一个我们称之为可以容纳四个块的缓存
So our our memory and then at the lower level we have memory
所以我们的记忆然后在较低的水平我们有记忆
And this memory is partitioned into blocks of some fixed size that's this
并且这个内存被划分为一些固定大小的块
That's the way cache is at nearly near the upper part of the hierarchy work
这就是缓存几乎接近层次结构工作上半部分的方式
Now at the lower levels like if you're accessing data say from a web server
现在处于较低级别，就像你从Web服务器访问数据一样
Then the the data is partitioned into files typically
然后通常将数据分区为文件
Okay but it upper levels the data is partitioned into blocks so just suppose this is main memory
好吧，但它的上层数据被分区为块，所以假设这是主内存
And then above that we have a that consists of a bunch of these blocks
然后，我们有一个由一堆这些块组成的
So we just take the memory and partition into blocks where each block is the same number of bytes
所以我们只需将内存和分区放入块中，每个块的字节数相同
And then data will be transferred between memory and the cache in block size transfer units
然后，数据将以块大小传输单位在内存和高速缓存之间传输
Okay so if you need data from the memory if the cache needs data from the memory it'll grab a whole block
好的，如果你需要来自内存的数据，如果缓存需要来自内存的数据，那么它将占用整个块
And then at any point in time the cache holds a subset of the the blocks in main memory
然后在任何时间点，高速缓存都保存主存储器中块的子集
Okay so this this cache is much faster but it's also much slower
好的，所以这个缓存要快得多，但速度也慢得多
And because of that and it's much smaller
因此，它要小得多
I'm sorry it's much faster but it's it's much more expensive because it's faster it's more expensive
我很抱歉它的速度要快得多，但它的价格却要贵得多，因为它的价格会更快，而且更贵
And because it's more expensive it's smaller
而且因为它更贵，所以它更小
Now suppose the cash once de-reference say that the CPU asks for data that's contained in block four
现在假设一旦取消引用现金，说CPU要求第4块中包含的数据
So it looks it looks to see if the data is in the cache it's not
因此看起来它看起来是否在数据库中是否存在数据
So the cache asks the memory to give it block four
所以缓存要求内存给它块四
So that block is copied from memory into the cache
这样块就会从内存复制到缓存中
Overwriting the one of the existing in this case block eight it will overwrite blockade
覆盖其中一个现有的块8，它将覆盖封锁
So now now block four is is in our cache
所以现在现在块四是在我们的缓存中
Now suppose now now suppose the CPU s for a some data that's in block ten
现在假设现在假设CPU为第10块中的一些数据
That gets copied up and and we overwrite that that block
这会被复制，我们会覆盖那个块
Now the whole idea of storing it in the cache is that we're hoping that the seek the program that's executing on the CPU
现在将它存储在缓存中的整个想法是我们希望寻找在CPU上执行的程序
Will reuse one of those blocks we just spent all the time
将重用我们刚刚花费的其中一个块
We went to all this trouble to copy it from memory to to this cache  and we know that's slow
我们把所有这些麻烦从内存复制到这个缓存，我们知道这很慢
So now suppose that the CPU needs some data in block  b in this case fourteen
所以现在假设CPU在块b中需要一些数据，在这种情况下是十四
Okay so it needs it needs a we're a memory word that's stored that was originally stored in memory it in block fourteen
好吧所以它需要它需要一个我们存储的存储器字，它最初存储在存储器中它在块14中
Well now this cache can just return that's what we call a hit right so the
那么现在这个缓存可以返回那个我们称之为右击的东西
Block that we access is in the cache so that's good hits are good
我们访问的块位于缓存中，因此良好的命中率很高
Because now we can return that block directly to CPU
因为现在我们可以将该块直接返回给CPU
And this this memory is much faster than if we had to go all the way to main memory to the DRAM
而且这个内存比我们必须一直到DRAM的主存储器要快得多
Okay so the SRAM much faster than the DRAM
好的，所以SRAM比DRAM快得多
So the CPU gets that block fourteen much faster than it would have
所以CPU比那个块快了十四倍
If it had just gone all the way to memory
如果它刚刚一直走向记忆
Okay the sort of other the the opposite of a hit is a miss
好吧，与命中相反的其他类型是一个错过
So suppose the CPU s for block twelve
假设CPU为12块
The cache looks for that block can't find it
缓存查找该块无法找到它
That's a miss so the the cash has to ask that the main memory the DRAM for block 12
这是一个小姐所以现金必须要求主要内存为块12的DRAM
Where it gets copied into the cache and then it can return that
它被复制到缓存中然后它可以返回它
So that takes longer right so the CPU has to wait for that block to be ex to be fetched from memory
所以这需要更长的时间，因此CPU必须等待从内存中取出该块
And so misses are slow so hits are good because they're fast
所以失误很慢所以命中很好，因为它们很快
Misses are bad because they're they're slow
错过很糟糕，因为他们很慢
Now we typically distinguish between several different kinds of caches
现在我们通常区分几种不同的缓存
So the first kind of miss is a cold miss or a compulsory miss
因此，第一种错过是冷漠或强制错过
Which is caused because there's just nothing in the cache
这是因为缓存中没有任何内容
Initially caches they're empty they have no blocks and as we fetch
最初缓存它们是空的，它们没有块，因为我们取了它们
As we fetch blocks from the lower level from the next the next level and put them in the cache
当我们从下一级别的下一级别获取块并将它们放入缓存中
The cache will slowly fill up with blocks
缓存将慢慢填满块
And we'll get and that will increase the likelihood of hits
而且我们会得到，这会增加点击的可能性
But when the cache is empty we're going to miss every time right
但是当缓存为空时，我们每次都会错过
So there's just no way to avoid cold misses right you got
所以没有办法避免你得到的冷缺失
Oh so this is called warming up your cache so as you load data items into the cache
哦，所以这称为预热缓存，以便将数据项加载到缓存中
Initially it's cold and as you add more items you're warming it up meaning that you're increasing the likelihood of a hit
最初它很冷，当你添加更多物品时，你正在升温它意味着你增加了击中的可能性
Now there's a there's another sort of symmetric kind of miss which is called a capacity miss
现在还有另一种对称的错过，称为容量未命中
And these misses are due to the fact that the cache is just a certain size right you just can't
而这些失误是由于缓存只是一个特定的大小，你不能
In the example we looked at we only had four blocks
在我们看到的例子中，我们只有四个块
So if we're if we're trying if our if our if our temporal locality involves eight blocks
因此，如果我们正在尝试，如果你的时间位置涉及八个块，那么你是否正在尝试
You know say if the loop that we're accessing is  is accessing elements in array
你知道我们正在访问的循环是否正在访问数组中的元素
That that consists of eight blocks there's just not enough room to store eight blocks and that four block cache
那个由8个块组成的空间不足以存储8个块和4个块缓存
So we're going to get misses right we would need a bigger cache to be able to satisfy and store those eight blocks
因此，我们将会遇到错误，我们需要更大的缓存才能满足并存储这8个块
And if we had a big enough cache then we get good hit rate right if we could store all the blocks
如果我们有足够大的缓存，那么如果我们可以存储所有块，我们就会获得良好的命中率
In our cache then we then then the cache could take advantage of the spatial and temporal locality within that program
然后我们在缓存中然后缓存可以利用该程序中的空间和时间局部性
So in general what we call this set of blocks at any point in time when a program is running
所以一般来说，在程序运行的任何时候我们称之为这组块
We call the set of blocks that are sort of being accessed over and over again the working set
我们调用一组块，这些块一次又一次地被访问工作集
And so your working set and the working set will change you know as you go from loop to loop  from function to function
因此，当你从一个循环到另一个循环从一个函数到另一个函数时，你的工作集和工作集将会改变
But at a point in time in your program when
但是在你的计划中的某个时间点
It you have this idea of a working set which is sort of the blocks that you need to have stored in your cache
你有一个工作集的想法，它是你需要存储在缓存中的块
Ok and well so when you're working set size exceeds your cache size then you get capacity misses
好的，所以当你的工作集大小超过你的缓存大小时，你就会遇到容量错过
There's this other kind of weird miss called the conflict miss
这是另一种奇怪的错过，称为冲突未命中
Which has to do with the way that caches are often implemented
这与经常实施缓存的方式有关
So the idea is that most caches especially hardware caches because they're they have to be simple
所以这个想法是大多数缓存特别是硬件缓存，因为它们必须简单
They have they limit where a block can be placed to some
他们限制了可以放置一些块的位置
Small set of positions in the cache
缓存中的一小组位置
So like one of the the simplest models is to just take
因此，像最简单的模型之一就是采取
Block I can only be placed in block I mod the cache size
块I只能放在块I中修改缓存大小
So in our that that little cache we saw that had four blocks
所以我们看到那个小缓存有四个块
We would take we would take block I from memory and we would stick it at block I mod 4
我们会采取从记忆中获取块I的方法，我们会将其粘贴在块I mod 4上
So block 0 would go at block 0 in our cache
所以块0将在我们的缓存中的块0处
As would block 4 and as would block 8 block 9 would go into block 1 in the cache
如块4和块8一样，块9将进入高速缓存中的块1
And that's when that happens suppose suppose we use that model so we're going to take
当发生这种情况时，假设我们使用该模型，那么我们就会采取这种模式
Block I and we're going to put it we can only place it in the cache
阻止我，我们将把它放在我们只能将它放在缓存中
At block I mod 4
在块I mod 4
Now suppose our suppose our reference pattern involves from memory block zero block four and block eight
现在假设我们假设我们的参考模式涉及内存块零块四和块八
It's only three blocks so we have we have enough room in the cache to store
它只有三个块，所以我们在缓存中有足够的空间来存储
Those three blocks but because of the way we've decided to place blocks each block will be will evict
这三个区块，但由于我们决定每个区块放置区块的方式将被逐出
When we access block four it'll go into block zero in the cache
当我们访问块4时，它将进入缓存中的块0
When we access blocked four in the cache
当我们在缓存中访问被阻止的四个时
It'll overwrite that block and it'll go into block zero in the cache
它会覆盖该块，它将进入缓存中的块0
And so because of this it's really the access pattern conspiring with the  algorithm
因此，正是这种访问模式与算法密切相关
That we're using for placing blocks
我们用于放置块
Okay so because of this we have plenty of room in the cache
好的，因此我们在缓存中有足够的空间
But because of this sort of the access pattern conspiring with the placement algorithm
但由于这种访问模式与放置算法密谋
We get misses every time
我们每次都会失误
We'll see how we'll see how conflict marisa's work in detail when we study your caches tomorrow
我们将在明天研究你的缓存时看到我们将如何看待冲突玛丽莎的详细工作
So
所以
So this is these these caches exist everywhere in the memory hierarchy and
所以这就是这些缓存存在于内存层次结构中的任何地方
So all of them are caches of one form or another right
所以它们都是各种形式的缓存
So you can think of the registers as a type of cache
因此，你可以将寄存器视为一种缓存
What are they cache for eight byte words
它们缓存八个字节的字是什么
Okay where's it cached it's cached right on the CPU itself
好吧，它缓存在哪里，它缓存在CPU本身上
What's the latency it's instant and happens within an instruction
什么是在指令中瞬间发生的延迟
And then who manages the cache somebody has to manage the cache when
然后谁管理缓存，有人必须在何时管理缓存
When when there's a request to load an item from the lower level in the hierarchy
何时请求从层次结构中的较低级别加载项目
Something has to decide what to do with that where to put it in the cache that's called managing the cache
有些东西必须决定如何处理将其放入称为管理缓存的缓存中的位置
Well in this case the compiler manages the cache
在这种情况下，编译器管理缓存
When you when you compile your C code the compiler figures out which register
当你编译C代码时，编译器会确定哪个寄存器
Data items from memory are going to go into okay
来自内存的数据项将进入正常状态
So tlb this is something this is a cache that's used in virtual memory
所以tlb这是一个在虚拟内存中使用的缓存
Then there's these hardware caches called l1 and l2 caches
然后是这些称为l1和l2缓存的硬件缓存
So they store 64 byte blocks on modern Intel systems
因此，它们在现代英特尔系统上存储64字节块
And they're cached on the CPU chip itself in in s ramps that are built right into the CPU chip
它们被安装在CPU芯片本身的高速缓存中，内置于CPU芯片中
And depending on whether l1 caches to on core i7s have a latency of 4 cycles
并且取决于l1缓存到核心i7上的延迟是4个周期
And l2 has a latency of 10 cycles
并且l2具有10个周期的延迟
And both of these are managed by hardware
这两者都是由硬件管理的
So when you when the CPU fetches an item from the l1 cache hardware figure finds it
所以，当你从l1缓存硬件中获取一个项目时，你会发现它
And if there's a miss and a block is loaded from l2 hardware in the l1 cache figures out where to put it
如果有一个未命中，并且l1高速缓存中的l2硬件加载了一个块，那么可以确定放置它的位置
Ok so all this is done without any intervention by hardware
好的，所有这些都是在没有硬件干预的情况下完成的
Disks contain buffer operating systems maintain buffer caches
磁盘包含缓冲区操作系统维护缓冲区缓存
So in this case what's cached is portions of files
所以在这种情况下，缓存的是文件的一部分
Ok and they're cached in main memory
好的，他们被缓存在主内存中
And latency to 2 main memories about a hundred cycles or so
并且延迟到2个主要记忆大约一百个左右
And these are managed by the operating system
这些都是由操作系统管理的
So the operating system reserves a portion of memory to store files that you've loaded so
因此，操作系统会保留一部分内存来存储你已加载的文件
So the operating system exploits locality if you if you read a file
因此，如果你阅读文件，操作系统将利用本地性
And then start reading referencing bytes from that file it will actually be served from the
然后开始从该文件中读取引用字节，它实际上将从该文件中提供
File cache and it won't go out to disk
文件缓存，它不会出现在磁盘上
Network networks maintain caches like things like nfs and afs maintain local caches on disk
网络网络维护像nfs这样的缓存，afs在磁盘上维护本地缓存
Your browser has a cache so when it fetches files from from servers
你的浏览器有缓存，因此从服务器获取文件时
It stores those files locally on disk so if you reference those web pages again
它将这些文件本地存储在磁盘上，以便再次引用这些网页
They're served from from your local disk rather than going all the way across the network
它们来自你的本地磁盘，而不是一直通过网络
Ok so the point is that these caches exist everywhere in the memory hierarchy
好的，关键是这些缓存存在于内存层次结构中的任何位置
And they're all based on the same principles they're just implemented in different ways
而且它们都基于相同的原则，它们只是以不同的方式实施
Ok so just to summarize what we've what we've done today
好的，只是总结一下我们今天所做的事情
We've seen that there's there's a gap between the CPU and our storage devices that continues to increase
我们已经看到CPU和我们的存储设备之间存在差距，这种差距在不断扩大
We've seen that well-written programs have this property called locality
我们已经看到编写良好的程序具有称为locality的属性
And we've seen that caching by taking by using caching
我们通过使用缓存看到了缓存
We can build a memory hierarchy that takes advantage of locality and programs
我们可以构建一个利用局部性和程序的内存层次结构
And allows us to build storage systems that where we can access data at the rate of the fastest device
并允许我们构建存储系统，以便以最快的设备速率访问数据
But at the cost and capacity of the devices at the the lowest level
但是在最低级别的设备的成本和容量
Ok so thursday we're going to look at a very specific part of the hierarchy called cache memories
好的星期四我们将看一个称为缓存的层次结构的一个非常具体的部分